matchbin.com 2006-05-13

# 

**Privacy Policy**

**At Matchbin we consider your privacy important. We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties without your explicit consent. Please read this Privacy Policy that you may understand how we use and protect your personal information.**

**Overview**  
The privacy policies contained herein apply to our services under the domain of www.matchbin.com and any of our affiliated partners whose websites clearly state that they are "Powered by **MATCHBIN** ". By visiting any of these websites you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree please do not use or access any of these sites.

This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect from you and what may happen with that information. Our policy is consistent throughout the MATCHBIN trading network and with any subsidiaries or joint ventures we may have.

By accepting the Privacy Policy and the Member Agreement in the registration process, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the MATCHBIN Members Agreement. This Privacy Policy is effective upon acceptance of registration for new registering users, and is otherwise effective on April 01, 2004 for all users.

**1\. Your Personal Information we Collect.**  
The primary purpose in collecting your personal information is to provide you with an effective, customized, and safe experience on our trading and forum network. Once you give us your personal information, you are not anonymous to MATCHBIN. Should you choose to use our services, you may be required to provide contact information, mailing information, billing information and other information as indicated on the forms throughout the site. Where possible, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional.

If you desire to list items or services on our trading network we may require additional information, such as financial information. We use your financial information, including credit card number, credit card billing address, expiration date, checking account name, address, bank routing number and bank account number to verify the accuracy of your name, address, and other information, as well as to bill you for your use of our services.

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of the MATCHBIN.com site and affiliated partner sites to help analyze our web page flow, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing our services. We offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie". We also use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can also help us provide information that is targeted to your interests. Most cookies are "session cookies", meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end on a session. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the Site and you may be required to reenter your password more frequently.

You may also encounter "cookies" or other similar devices on certain pages of MATCHBIN.com site or our affiliated partner sites that are placed by third parties. MATCHBIN does not control the use of cookies by third parties.

If you choose to bid, buy, or sell on the MATCHBIN.com site or any of our affiliated partner sites, we DO NOT collect information about your transactions. As stated in our Member Agreement, MATCHBIN.com is a matching venue and "is not a participant in any type of transaction".

We also collect member comments concerning you in our feedback area. If you choose to post messages in our message area or leave feedback for other users, we will collect that information you provide us. We retain this information to provide customer support and empower users as they use the trade network. 

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or listings on the MATCHBIN.com or our affiliated partner sites, we may collect such information into a file specific for you.

**2\. Information on Minors NOT ALLOWED.**  
It is MATCHBIN policy that "Our services are not available to minors; however, minors may use the service in conjunction with a parent or guardian". Minors are considered persons under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, you may not submit personal information on this Site. If you are a minor, you may only use this Site in conjunction with and under the supervision of your parents or guardians. 

**3\. Our Use of Your Personal Information.**  
We use the information you give to us to facilitate the services that you request. We use your personal information to: facilitate trade negotiations between users throughout the trade network; troubleshoot account problems; collect the purchase of listing packages; inform you about online and offline offers, product, services, and updates; detect and protect against error, fraud and other criminal activity; enforce our member agreement; help promote safe trading; comply with any government regulation; facilitate use of discussion, chat or forum venues on the site; measure consumer interest in our products and services; and as otherwise described to you at the time of information collection. We may compare and review your personal information for errors, omissions and for accuracy.

You agree that should you choose to list "haves" or "wants" on MATCHBIN.com or any affiliated partner site, the financial information you have provided us will be used to bill you and provide you with ongoing support.

You agree that we may use your personal information to benefit our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze site usage, improve our content, product and services offerings, and customize MATCHBIN.com’s site with respect to content, layout and other services.

You agree that we may use your information to contact you and deliver information to you, in some cases, are targeted to your interests, such as targeted banner advertisements, administrative notices, product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of the Site. By accepting the Member Agreement and Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information.

**4\. Our Disclosure of Your Personal Information.**  
At MATCHBIN we do not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. The following describes some of the ways in which your personal information may be disclosed in the normal course of business as we provide our users with our services.

MATCHBIN Trade Network. After registration, every member has the ability to determine the extent to which they would like their personal information shared on the Trade Network. Members may choose to keep all of their personal information private (except mandatory-shared information such as user screen name, city, state, country) or share all of their personal information. Your mandatory-shared information is displayed throughout the Network and is therefore available to the public. Your personal information that is optional to share is: first name, last name, address, postal code, phone number, and email address. You do not have to share your optional personal information on the network. Also, your user name and password are never displayed to the public. However, you have the ability to change your password if necessary. The Privacy Options section of a member’s account is the place where changes to personal information can be made. It has been the policy of MATCHBIN for users to freely trade amongst themselves without interference from us. We encourage the free flow of information (including personal information) in order for trade negotiations to be completed.

When a member opens a trade negotiation with another user, the system sends an internal message to that user indicating that the initiating member has a trade offer. Both initiating member and potential trade user receive sufficient personal information to either proceed or terminate with the trade negotiation. Trade negotiations are never monitored by MATCHBIN or its affiliated trade partners and all personal information is strictly between the two (or in some cases three) negotiating parties.

MATCHBIN "Talk" and "Meet" Venues. As with the MATCHBIN Trade Network, every member has the ability to determine the extent to which they would like their personal information shared on the "Talk" Venue and/or the "Meet" Venue on the MATCHBIN.com site. The Privacy Options section of a member’s account is the place where changes to personal information can be made. Should a member choose to send personal information, of any kind, whether it be information contained in the "personal information" section of the member account page or any other personal information that the member deems to share with other members on the MATCHBIN network; member holds MATCHBIN Inc harmless and releases MATCHBIN Inc from consequences of dissemination of personal information sent freely by member. MATCHBIN Inc has no control over personal information disseminated other than such personal information contained on the member’s "personal information" section of the members account page.

**Internal Service Providers**. We may use third parties to help facilitate certain aspects of our business that we provide for you and therefore we may provide some of your personal information directly to these internal service providers. These internal service providers are subject to confidentiality agreements with us and other legal restrictions that prohibit their use of the information we provide them for any other purpose or reason other than the specific service they are providing for us. If you provide additional information to an internal service provider directly, then their use of your personal information is regulated by their applicable privacy policy.

**Legal Requests**. Due to subpoenas, court orders, government regulations and our rights to defend against legal claims, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Although we strive to protect your privacy, we cannot guarantee, nor should you expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

**5\. Knowledge and use of other users’ information.**  
Because our service allows users to freely exchange information with one another, by entering into our Member Agreement, you agree, with respect to other users’ personal information that you obtain through the MATCHBIN.com site or any of our affiliated partner sites, that MATCHBIN Inc hereby grants to you a license to use such information only for: (a) MATCHBIN or affiliated partner related communications that are not unsolicited commercial messages, and (b) any other purpose that a user expressly agrees to after you tell them the purpose you would like to use it for. Under no circumstances, except as defined in this section, can you disclose information about another user to any third party without the consent of that user. You agree that other users may use your personal information to communicate with you in accordance with this section. You agree to give users an opportunity to remove themselves from your database and review what information you may have collected about them. MATCHBIN and its affiliated partners will not tolerate Spam. You are not licensed to add a MATCHBIN or affiliated partner user or member, even a user who has purchased an item or service from you, to your mailing list without their express consent.

**6\. Control of your Password**.  
You are responsible for all actions taken with your User ID and password. We recommend that you do not disclose your User ID or password to any third parties. Should you share your User ID and password or your personal information with third parties, you are responsible for all actions taken with your account. We recommend that you review any third party Privacy Policies. If your password has been compromised, you should immediately change your password. If you lose control of your password you may lose control of your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf.

**7\. Changing your Personal Information.**  
We give you the ability to review and change the personal information you have submitted to us. This is done by logging into any MATCHBIN powered site and entering your new information. Generally, MATCHBIN will not modify your personal information because it is very difficult to authenticate your account manually. We recommend that you promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate.

Upon your request, we will deactivate your account, including contact information, billing information, and shipping information, from our active databases. To make this request, email us at support@matchbin.com. Such information will be deactivated as soon as reasonably possible. However, we retain in our files some personal information you have requested to be removed to prevent fraud, assist with any investigations, enforce our policies and comply with any legal requirements as permitted by law. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personal information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your request. However, such personal information will be deactivated from public and member viewing.

**8\. Security.**  
Your personal information is stored on MATCHBIN servers located in the United States of America. We use a variety of safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access, including encryption, "firewalls" and Secure Socket Layers. However, 100% totally secure and safe protection does not exist on the Internet.

**9\. Notice of Policy Amendment.**  
We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on the MATCHBIN.com and/or affiliated partner sites. All amended terms shall automatically be effective 30 days after they are initially posted.
